DANISH SHAKEEL





danishshakeel54@gmail.com



+91 7006 250 627



https://danishshakeel.me



1217, Housing Colony Ompora, Budgam, Jammu & Kashmir, India – 191111



Chandigarh University, Gharuan, Punjab, India

CORE COMPETENCIES

Full Stack Development

Machine Learning and Data Science

Research and Content Writing

Graphic Designing

Creativity and Problem Solving

Commercial and Industry Awareness

Trustworthiness and Ethics

EDUCATION

Current 8.2 CGPA

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering (Hons.)

Chandigarh University

Intermediate 86.8%

2018-2022 (expected)
Central Board of Secondary
Education
2017-2018

Secondary 8.8 CGPA **Central Board of Secondary Education**2015-2016

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

One of the youngest technocrats (at the age of 14) from Kashmir and a Digital India Award recipient, with around one year of industry experience, and seven publications. A challenge-driven and ingenious professional seeking to leverage advanced technologies, particularly in AI, Full Stack Development, Research, and Healthcare.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Core Team (Tech/Graphics) | Hackoverflow Technical Society
 Voluntarily contributing to the students' society in the department of design
 and development.
 [August 2020 – Present]

- 2. Data Science Intern | Sher-i-Kashmir Institute of Medical Sciences
 To research the use of artificially intelligent tools to assist pharmacotherapy.
 Developed model for drug administration, and published one paper.
 [April 2020 July 2020]
- 3. Full Stack Developer (Intern) | Flickhire Dubai
 To plan, design, develop, and deploy the website.
 [August 2019 October 2019]
- 4. IT Intern (Tech and Product) | EzeSkool Dubai To research similar platforms, systematically plan, design, and develop the website, deploy the website, and administrate it. [June 2019 – August 2019]

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Self-reported adherence to pharmacotherapy in cancer patients [IJBCP, Jun. 2020]
- 2. Personalized drug concentration predictions with machine learning: an exploratory study [IJBCP, Jun. 2020]
- 3. **Doctors' self-prescribing behavior: an exploratory study** [IJRMS, Jan. 2020]
- 4. Insect Detection and Flight Tracking in a Controlled Environment Using Machine Vision: Review of Existing Techniques and an Improved Approach [ICCR, Elsevier SSRN Conference Proceedings, Jan. 2020]
- 5. Comparative assessment of antibiotic self-medication practices among undergraduate medical students and general population [JRMS, Dec. 2019]
- 6. The impact of information and communication technologies (ICTs) on academic performance of medical students: an exploratory study [IJRMS, Feb. 2019]
- 7. Assessment of medication adherence among patients with chronic diseases: a descriptive cross-sectional study [IJBCP, Dec. 2018]

PROFILES



/danishshakeel



/danish17



/Danish_Shakeel3



Google Scholar

TRAITS & SOFT SKILLLS



Problem Solving



Versatility & Adaptability



Time Management



Creative Thinking



Attention to Detail



Leadership



Conflict Resolution



Communication Skills

HARD SKILLS



Proficient in C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3



Strong Knowledge of Machine Learning, and Data Science



Strong knowledge of Full Stack Tech and frameworks (JAM, Python)



Experience in Data Management and Databases (SQL)



Cloud Services, IaaS, PaaS



Graphic Designing and Prototyping



Analytical Reasoning



Foundational Knowledge of Quantum Computation

PROJECTS AND APPS

1. Drug Administration using Machine Learning [April 2020]

A population-based drug administration tool for Phenytoin and Valproic acid serum levels, and dosage.

Proof of concept – https://drug-administration-ml.herokuapp.com

2. Litmus Fake News Detector [February 2020]

A language-feature-multi-model-ensemble-based machine learning model (tool) to detect false news.

Proof of concept – https://litmus-ai-web.herokuapp.com

3. Used Car Prices Predictor [February 2020]

A Flask-based Random Forest Regression to predict used Indian car prices. Repository - https://github.com/danish17/used-car-prices-india

4. Text Analysis in Pure C [November 2018]

A command-line-utility for text analysis using Levenshtein Distance.

Repository - https://github.com/danish17/textanalysisinc

5. My Kashmir (and other apps) [2015]

Information-based local android app, with phone directory, news, etc.

Play Store - https://shorturl.at/rA259

AWARDS, ACHIEVEMENTS, AND CERTIFICATIONS

Awards and Achievements

- 1. Digital India Cyber Security Champion, Government of India [2015]
- 2. 1st International Cyber Olympiad, EduHeal Foundation [2015]
- 3. 1st 42nd National Science Exhibition, Kendriya Vidyalaya Sangthan [2015]
- 4. 3rd International Science Olympiad, EduHeal Foundation [2015]
- 5. Top 10, All Time Papers Bioenvironmental Engineering, Elsevier SSRN
- 6. Excellent Soft Skills DCPD, Chandigarh University [2019]
- 7. Top 50 NFLAT, National Center for Financial Education [2015]
- 8. Best Student, Jawahar Institute of Mountaineering and Winter Sports [2013]

Certificates

- 1. IBM Advanced Data Science | IBM
- 2. IBM Data Science Professional Certificate | IBM
- 3. The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing | Google
- 4. Google Analytics Individual Qualification | Google
- 5. Python for Data Science | NPTEL, IIT Madras
- **6. Customer Service Specialist** | Aspiring Minds
- 7. Data Processing Specialist | Aspiring Minds
- 8. English Comprehension | Aspiring Minds
- 9. Al From the Data Center to the Edge | Intel Corp.
- **10. Web Development Using HTML** | SBS Info Systems